Guide to the Cullen College of Engineering Records
University of Houston Libraries
Cullen College of Engineering Records
1940-2009
2009-017
Cullen College of Engineering
10.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
These records contain 10 boxes relating to the Cullen College of Engineering at the University of Houston. A significant portion of this material was given to the archives from the university Print Plant.
Historical Note:
The Department of Engineering was formed in 1934 with the chartering of the University, and in the school year 1939-1940 it became one of the most popular departments in the University. During the first long-term on their new campus, 397 students took engineering courses in the new air-cooled Roy Gustav Cullen Memorial Building. This was approximately one-seventh of the enrollment of the University at the time. [1]
In the fall of 1947, the University of Houston established the Co-op Program. The primary purpose of the Co-operative Program was to help students gain practical experience and to supplement their studies in either the Engineering or Business schools. This program still exists today under the name Co-operative Education. [2]
Mr. and Mrs. H.R. Cullen had been the principal benefactors of the University and, in particular, the College of Engineering for many years. In 1958 there was a great deal of sentiment expressed to change the name of the University to Cullen University. The Cullens refused the honor since they felt that its identity and its role with respect to the community would be affected. Their name was therefore given to the College of Engineering. [3]
One year after the official name change, a Building Dedication Ceremony was held for the brand new Cullen College of Engineering Building on May 3, 1968. This ceremony included the unveiling of a framed portrait of H. R. Cullen which still hangs today. [4]
The University of Houston Cullen College of Engineering is accredited by the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology. Today, more than 2,600 students are enrolled in engineering courses—1,840 undergraduates, 78 post-baccalaureates, 725 masters and doctoral students in biomedical, chemical, civil, computer, electrical, environmental, industrial, and mechanical engineering. The college also offers graduate programs in aerospace, environmental, industrial power systems, materials, and petroleum engineering. Chemical Engineering and Mechanical Engineering have ranked among the top programs nationally. [5]
Sources:
[1] “University of Houston Department of Engineering 1940-1941” pamphlet (box 1, folder 1)
[2] “The Co-Operative Division April 14, 1948” (box 1, folder 2)
[3] “A History of Engineering” by William J. Leach (box 1, folder 5)
[4] “Cullen College of Engineering Building Dedication” program (box 1, folder 5)
[5] College Facts, available from www.egr.uh.edu. 12 August 2009.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Cullen College of Engineering; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration.; University of Houston
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
These records contain 10 boxes relating to the Cullen College of Engineering at the University of Houston. A significant portion of this material was given to the archives from the university Print Plant. Material includes event programs and flyers, co-op program material, newsletters, brochures, correspondence, stationary, course lectures, and published material. Included in this collection are the following series: General Information, Mechanical Engineering NASA Class Lectures, and Publications. This collection is arranged alphabetically by department title, and chronologically as necessary. Class lectures are arranged alphabetically while published material is arranged chronologically. Material ranges in date from the 1940s to 2009.
Detailed List of Contents
- General Information
  - Academic events, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Co-Op program, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Academic events, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Academic events, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brief History of the UH College of Engineering, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Co-Op program, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters and brochures, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Academic events, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Co-Op program, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters and brochures, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Academic events, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Co-Op program, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters and brochures, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Academic events, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters and brochures, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Academic events, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters and brochures, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Stationery (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - undated (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
  - Biomedical Engineering, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Biomedical Engineering, 2000’s (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, undated (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, 2000s (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering - Petroleum Engineering, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering - Petroleum Engineering, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering - Petroleum Engineering, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering - Petroleum Engineering, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering - Petroleum Engineering, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering - Petroleum Engineering, 2000s (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Civil and Environmental Engineering, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Civil and Environmental Engineering, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Civil and Environmental Engineering, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Civil and Environmental Engineering, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - Civil and Environmental Engineering, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Civil and Environmental Engineering, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Civil and Environmental Engineering, 2000s (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Civil and Environmental Engineering - Geotechnical Engineering, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Civil and Environmental Engineering - Ocean Engineering, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Civil and Environmental Engineering - Structural Engineering, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 2000s (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Industrial Engineering, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Industrial Engineering, 1940s (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Industrial Engineering, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Industrial Engineering, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Industrial Engineering, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Industrial Engineering, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Industrial Engineering, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Industrial Engineering, 2000s (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Industrial Engineering - Distribution and Logistics, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Mechanical Engineering, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Mechanical Engineering, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Mechanical Engineering, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 27-28)
  - Mechanical Engineering, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Mechanical Engineering, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Mechanical Engineering, 2000s (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Engineering flyers, undated (Drawer F.9, Ovs folder 7)
- Mechanical Engineering NASA Class Lectures
  - “Fourier Analysis of SAG in Apollo” (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - “Mission Objectives & Design Implications” (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - “Real Time Deep Space Television” (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - “Space Contamination Due to Manned Vehicles” (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - “Guidance and Control Requirements in a Space Mission” (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - “Overall Design Concepts” (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "The Definition of the Space Environment for Manned Space Vehicles” (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - “Structural Materials-Metallic” (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - “Thermal Balance and Heat” (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - “Dynamic Environment” (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - “The Study of Man in Space” (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - “Life Support Systems” (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - “Operation of Manned Spacecraft” (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - “Electrical Power Systems” (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - “Power Distribution and Sequencing” (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - “Introduction to Guidance and Control Series” (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - “Stabilization and Control Systems” (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - “Problems in Space Navigation and Guidance” (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - “Guidance Systems Design” (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - “Solid Rocket Lecture” (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - “Reaction Control Systems for Manned Spacecraft” (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - “Pyrotechnics” (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - “Airborne Instrumentation” (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - “Launch Escape Systems” (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Launch Vehicles and Launch Vehicle-Spacecraft Integration” (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - “Earth Landing for Manned Spacecrafts” (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - “Project Gemini Design Integration” (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - "Apollo Design Integration” (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - “Lunar Excursion Module Design Integration” (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - “Reliability through Attention to Detail” (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - “Mission Planning and Philosophy” (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - “Preflight Checkout and Preparation” (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - “Simulators and Training for Manned Space Flight” (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - “Inflight Systems Monitoring” (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - “Summary of Management, Design, and Operational Philosophy” (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Publications
  - A Mobile Water Treatment Research Facility for removing Inorganic containments, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Chemical Engineering - Graduate Study, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Communications Systems for manned Interplanetary Explorations, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Computers and Programming (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Electrical Engineering - Graduate Study, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Mechanical Engineering - Graduate Study, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - New Technology Program List of Active Projects, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Research Capabilities, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - The Design of Spring and Threads, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - The Marvels of Engineering, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Writing lists in Technical Documents, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - A survey of Industrial Engineering Functions and Personnel, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Accuracy tests on Models 10-FV-01 and 10-CV-01, Vol-u-meters, July 15, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Tests on Insulating Properties of WECO FIG 211 Unions, December 2, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Vocational and Professional Monographs Petroleum Engineering, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Industrial Engineering Conference, November 7, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Proceedings of the Seventh Annual Industrial Engingeering Conference, November 3, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - PERT and PERT/COST, February 9, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Investigation of Relations between Solar Variations & Weather on Earth, October 1963 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Proceedings: International Symposium on lubrication & wear, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Proceedings of the Tenth Annual Industrial Engineering Conference, November 20, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Estimations of Signal-to-Noise Ratio, April 1965 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Final Report, Spetember 15, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Proceedings of the Eleventh Annual Industrial Engineering Conference, November 12, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - The Case for Graduate Engineering Education in Latin America, March 1, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Proposal for a hybrid computing facility, October 10, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Proposal to the National Aeronautics 7 Space Administration, November 12, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Balancing criteria & their relationship to current American Pract., March 1967 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Proposal to the National Science Foundation for sponsorship, April 15, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Concerning the stability of a flexible shaft w/one disk, May 1967 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Analog & Digital simulations of multiplex system performance, June 1967 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Proposal for a doctor of Philosophy degree program in Industrial Engineering, June 1967 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Proceedings Houston-Galveston Area Urban transportation in persp, March 1968 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Longitudinal Pressure Waves in a fluid column, March 6, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - MODE Response of a sinusoidally, excited, circular bimorph, June 1968 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Final Report of the NSF advanced science seminar, Summer 1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Evaluation of Acoustic response of an air-water siren, July 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The testing & performance of a wide-band underwater liquid communicator, August 1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chemical Engineering - Graduate Study, December 4, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - a planned steam-energy monitoring capability for the Texas City Refinery, December 13, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - An Analytic solution for whirl in a finite journal bearing with a continuous lubricating film, January 1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - A digital computer program to determine the expected mean squares, March 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Selection of a hybrid computing facility, May 1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - indentification and properties of expansive clays, August 1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - On the stability of poiseuille pipe flow, August 1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Development of a prototype ‘task board” for metabolic & other exper, August 29, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Drawings & parts list for Prototype task board, August 29, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - QUASI solution of multipoint boundary value problems, September 1969 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - UHELP user’s manual, October 1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Chemical & petroleum engineering - Graduate Study, February 9, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - UHCAP user’s manual, May 1970 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Dielectric field computations in semi conductor oxide integrated circuits, July 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Semi-conductor integrated circuit component models, July 1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - PRODYC, a simulation prog. for chemical process dynamics & cont., August 1970 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Additional research on pipeline flotation, August 24, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - A translator for dynamo to CSMP in PL/I, September 1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Comparison of techniques to determine the mode of unimodal func, October 1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - A translator for dynamo to CSMP in PL/I, October 1970 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Comparison of integer programming codes, October 1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Review conference, November 20, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - The use of Quasilinerarization as an Identification Techn, December 1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Water Resources planning for the Houston-Galveston Region, January 18, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - GRAID - Graphical aid computer language, March 1971 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Television system for continuing engineering & business education, June 1971 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - FGORC Admin. Final Report, September 15, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Final Report, September 15, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - The influence of surf. active contamin. on the inter. between wind & waves, October, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Elements of experimental heat transfer, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - UHSE Newsletter, Fall 1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Process Design & Simulation, February 4, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Building a Lunar Colony, September 15, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Proposal for a program of faculty engineering systems design instit, Summer 1973 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Proposal to the National Aeronautics & space admin, Summer 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Control equipment design 7 analysis, CEDA, January 1973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Final Report of application of remote sensing Contract, January 10, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Proceedings of the 20th anniversary symposium mass transfer & diff., April 5-6, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Proceedings of a conf. on research needs & priorities in catalysis, April 13, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - National Indus. Economic models off water use & waste treatment, April 19, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Rheology of Viscoplastic crude oils, May 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Cellsim User’s manual, August, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Final Report, September 15, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Charge by the governor to the energy advisory council, December 5, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Character. of heat transfer in nutrient materials, December 31, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Energy Recovery Solid Waste vol. 1 Summary Report, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Energy Report from Solid Waste vol. 2 Technical Report, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Final Report of application of remote sensing Contract, January 10, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Summary Report on the December 10, 1973 public hearing, January 23, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - The state of Texas Governor’s Energy Advisory Council, February 7, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Solar Thermal power systems based on optical transmission, February 15, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Membership, February 20, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Potential for Selective Standards for Air Pollution Control, March 13, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - The Four Program Core Charts, March 19, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Engineering: Man Working for Mankind, April 4, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - The state of Texas Governor’s Energy Advisory Council, June 6, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - A summary of the objectives, program & management plan, June 17, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Evolving an Energy Policy for Texas, July 29, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - September - Graduate Programs, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Intermittent (SLUG) Flow of two phase, gas-liquid mixtures, December 1974 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Solar Thermal Power systems based on optical transmission, December 21, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Solar Thermal Power systems based on optical transmission, December 31, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Applications of Heterogeneous Catalysis, January 27-31, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Executive summaries of Project Reports of the Council, March 1, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Measurement of the effects of surface geometry modification, March 10, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Hydrogen Production Econometric Studies, May 1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Applications of Heterogeneous Catalysis, May 12-16, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - A proposal for Analysis Design, Fabrication, & Testing, July 7, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - The Evaluation of Surface Geometry Modifications, September 11, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Solar Thermal Power Systems based on Optical Transmission, October 21, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Chemical Engineering, Graduate Studies, October 22, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - A parameter study of distress in buildings constructed, November 1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Annual Research Summary, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Report of Activities, Energy Institute, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Final Technical Report, Feb. 15 & 14, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Development of a prototype ‘task board” for metabolic & other expert, August 29, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Chemical Engineering, Graduate Studies, October 15, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Annual Research Summary, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Liquid Metal Cooled, May 1977 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - A Review of the Methods for predicting Dynamo & Kinematic, August 1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fact Book on Major Texas Electric Utilities, August 1977 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Proceedings of the ERDA Solar Workshop, August 10-11, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Liquid Metal Cooled Solar Central Receiver, October 1977 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Applications of Heterogeneous Catalysis, October 25, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Workshop supply & demand of Hydrogen, December 12-14, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Annual Research Summary, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Application of a structured decision process for proper inclusion, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Chemical Engineering department - “Sulfur in Fossil Fuels”, January 9-11, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Annual Report underground antennas for radio commun, February 28, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Rate of Industrial Energy conversation Petroleum Refining, April 1978 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Civil Engineering - Graduate Studies, May 26, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The prevention of cam mechanism separation using a retaining spring, June 1978 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Retrofit sizing & economics of air pre-heaters & economizers, September 1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Responses of moored objects to water waves part II, October 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Notes on collector field optimization-extensions of Basic Theory, November 1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - The sensitivity analysis of cam mechanism dynamics, December 1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Annual Research Summary, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Electronics for Scientists & Engineers, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Improved combustion efficiences-combustion control systems, January 1979 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Sulfur in Fossil Fuels & Desulfurization Technology, Feb. 12-15, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Promes, March 1979 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Texas Energy in Transition: An initial effort to focus, April 30, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Semi-Annual Progress Review seismic acoustics laboratory, May 7, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Technical Report, A comprehensive study of subsurface propagation, June 1, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Preliminary activities in the development of MX maintenance, September 1979 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Annual Report, Department of Mechanical Engineer, September 1 & August 31, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Engineering South Park Annex office & Lab. Construction, October 2, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - High temperature electronics & instrumentation seminar, December 3-4, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - A description of the capabilities of the individual Heliostat Code, July 1980 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - A programmer’s manual for UH computer code RCELL, September 1980 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Application of a design morphology to the MX/OCC, September 1980 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Annual Report, Dept. of Mechanical Engineering, September 1 & August 31, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - A user’s manual for the UH Solar Central Receiver vol. 1, December 1980 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - A user’s manual for UH Solar Central Receiver vol. 2, December 1980 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Annual Research Summary, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - March, Heliostat Systems: Technical & Economic Assessment, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Sizing & Costing Solar/Fuel fired Cogeneration plants for Texas, August 1981 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Biomedical Engineering - Graduate Studies, August 12, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 30)